Revanth Ettikkan

Software Engineer

+91 9894050477· revanthgit@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/revanthettikkan/

A motivated and adaptable Software Engineer with 2.6 years of experience in the insurance industry, focused on developing user-friendly applications. Demonstrated ability to refine application logic, ensure data accuracy, and optimize system performance using Java, Spring Boot, and related technologies. Hands-on experience with SQL/NoSQL databases, CI/CD pipelines, and AWS.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Java
- Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA
- Spring AOP, Spring MVC
- JUnit, Mockito

- REST API, My SQL
- MongoDB, Spring Security
- Python, Bamboo CI/CD, AWS, Microservices
- JavaScript, Splunk, Hibernate

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cognizant Technology Solutions | Software Engineer | (Coimbatore/TN)

11/2022 - Present

- Liberty Mutual Insurance
 - Refined application logic in Java to Accurately Classify Heavy and Refined application Logic in Java to Accurately Classify Heavy and Extra-Heavy Trucks/Tractors, meeting acceptance criteria and improved quote pricing.
 - Implemented a java-based solution to address the issue of duplicate location data generation, resulting in accurate quote pricing.
 - Worked with relational databases, such as MySQL, PostgreSQL and object-relational mapping frameworks like Spring Data JPA.
 - Optimized Log Levels and Removed Unnecessary Logs to Prevent Log Capacity Issues and Enhance System Performance.
 - Worked on updating Business Group Codes in DBs through Liquibase to categorize businesses.
 - Developed comprehensive JUnit tests for new features and bug fixes.
 - Updated RDS Certificate Authority Certificates in AWS for few applications to Enhance Security and Compliance.
 - Performed UAT testing.
 - Used agile methodologies to plan and execute software development projects.
 - Support for production release activity.
 - Created Wiki page for all the new issues as a handy to resolve in quick time.

Forge | Innovation Engineer Trainee | (Coimbatore/TN)

08/2021 - 01/2022

- ProtoSem is a 20-week fellowship program that develops students' technical skills and transforms them into "Innovation Engineers".
- Students work in teams to design, develop, and test a tech-based solution to a real-world problem, resulting in a minimum viable prototype.
- I had an opportunity to learn and work on a Machine Learning project.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (Computer Science Engineering), Kumaraguru College of Technology, India

06/2018 - 06/2022

AWS Cloud Practitioner GitHub Co-Pilot